<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Holmes Lab</title>
    <link>https://ihh.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Holmes Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ian Holmes, 2020 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ihh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JBrowseR: An R Interface to the JBrowse 2 Genome Browser</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/jbrowser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/jbrowser/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annabel Large</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/annabel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/annabel/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student in the Bioengineering Graduate Group at UC Berkeley and UC San Francisco. I&amp;rsquo;m working on developing statistical and machine learning models to better characterize and understand the engineering of Adeno-associated viral capsids, specifically what&amp;rsquo;s going on during the process of directed evolution.
In my free time, I enjoy exploring the Bay Area, folding origami, and a host of podcasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair consensus decoding improves accuracy of neural network basecallers for nanopore sequencing</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/poreover/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/poreover/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordi Silvestre-Ryan</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/jordi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/jordi/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD candidate in the joint UC Berkeley-UCSF Bioengineering program and am broadly interested in applications of deep learning to biology. During my PhD I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on computational approaches to improve the accuracy of nanopore sequencing. I also maintain interests in structural biology and data vizualization, and have developed a tool for making simplified cartoons of protein structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A model of indel evolution by finite-state, continuous-time machines</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/automata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/automata/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Boss: rapid prototyping of bioinformatic automata</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/machineboss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/machineboss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellular automata simulation of RNA self-replicators</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/carnaval/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/carnaval/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Product Owner: A New Role In Academic Software</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/post/research-product-owner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/post/research-product-owner/</guid>
      <description>(Cross-posted from ianholmes.wordpress.com)
The idea behind the JBrowse project has always been to bring the standards of commercial software development to genomics.
JBrowse was originally an attempt to bring genome browsers up to the usability standards of commercial web apps. In the 1990s, bioinformatics led the web: Lincoln Stein (a co-PI of JBrowse) wrote the CGI.pm module that was used to power sites like Amazon in the early days, as well as his genome browser GBrowse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shihab Dider</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/shihab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/shihab/</guid>
      <description>In college, I worked in the area of structural systems pharmacology, trying to understand the side-effects of common drugs (like Metformin) by examining the structure and function of their putative off-targets. Currently, I am working on algorithms and tools for facilitating genomics on the web, such as in-browser approximate alignment and track recommendation systems for genomic browsers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apollo: democratizing genome annotation</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/apollo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/apollo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioMake: a GNU make-compatible utility for declarative workflow management</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/biomake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/biomake/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historian: accurate reconstruction of ancestral sequences and evolutionary rates</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/historian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/historian/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ian Holmes</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/ian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/ian/</guid>
      <description>In the 80&amp;rsquo;s, as an 8-bit game developer, I became interested in artificial life. In the 90&amp;rsquo;s I studied physics, then did a PhD on molecular evolution of transposons in the nematode genome, advised by Richard Durbin at the Sanger Institute. Then I came to Berkeley (via Los Alamos) to think about RNA.
In 2004 I moved from my first faculty job at Oxford&amp;rsquo;s Department of Statistics (2002-2004) to join the faculty on UC Berkeley, going from a postdoc on an exchange visa (1999-2002) to co-chair of the Bioengineering PhD program (2019-23).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Buels</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/rob/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/rob/</guid>
      <description>I got my start in genomics right out of school as a software engineer at the Sol Genomics Network, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been in research software engineering ever since, with one tour of duty in industry at Foundation Medicine.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with JBrowse since 2012, and now I am the software team lead for JBrowse 2.
I&amp;rsquo;m much more of an engineer and software architect than a scientist, but I understand enough of the science to be dangerous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JBrowse: a dynamic web platform for genome visualization and analysis</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/jbrowse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/jbrowse/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking statistical and ecological theory: Hubbell&#39;s unified neutral theory of biodiversity as a hierarchical Dirichlet process</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/hubbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/hubbell/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAV ancestral reconstruction library enables selection of broadly infectious viral variants</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/publication/aav/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/publication/aav/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/approach/</guid>
      <description>Et malis vellet tellus deseruere in credant Inde sidera moenia lacertis nomen nostra membra Lorem markdownum miranti. Sonus faciunt omnibus frustra: illa possem ad regio Anubis tamen. Sustulerat debent fluviis herbis attollere rogus et formae nitentem avellere motis clipeus Achilles felix videam undas. Posuit haec ipse posse.
Ore fame mons Olympi tantae stringit columbas proxima habebat, longius alta non. Haeserat gerunt detinuit genis est huc, dixit tam dumque nitidum.
 Cristata causam Triones moenia habentem subito utentem Astraea castris contentus nisi leve eum invia Inferiusque capta cognoscenda flaventi locuta notavi fallere Moriens scripsi ictus tuo cum  Tarpeias insurgens summo sinistra vertice, in neve utroque exempla Cyparissus tanta tecti terras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/mission/</guid>
      <description>Auras queritur facientes dixit venti sustinui E in mora Lorem markdownum poenaque nuper destituit silendo quoniam, nec ait consorte membra, figuram hanc cum. Manifesta vitae facies exiguumque iunctam dictis. Vidit eadem, hanc cum descendit sinu misit quem fecit, positisque pastorve. Missus solos potentia in erant noctem est!
if (dvdProcessorVolume &amp;lt; mpegProcess(slashdot, gigahertz)) { transferAnsiBotnet.and(logSoftware, hsfClipboardSubnet.queue_publishing( systemMemory, 5, yahoo)); } else { swappableIpv -= spoolingAdwareCrossplatform; extranetAppArchitecture(1, dtd_rpc_font(45, 67, development_sli)); } antivirus_ipv = touchscreenFiosGrep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Biological applications  Cancer genomics Virus evolution Protein engineering  Tools and models  Deep learning Bayesian statistics Phylogenetics Web development  Projects  JBrowse Synthetic biology Evolution Nanopore  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/vacancy/vacancy1/</guid>
      <description>You can write $\LaTeX$ and Markdown here.
Minyae adgnoscitque fugiebat parentis ausum superos huius Ait erili meruisse iactatis omnibus erat Lorem markdownum natis, ipsi ipsi aut relictus saxo comitantibus aegro amori verba fugisse mira mortisque leones! Prior sui liquidissimus leve properandum totidem studio, refert magno, me quibus. Sternitur discordia summaque, si deus in undam et vulnere dirusque est felices pallam miserere curvamine comites. Tegumenque decipit suis, poscitur una dea sumus adnuerant, gerebat est edam plura.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colin Diesh</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/colin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/colin/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a self-styled &amp;ldquo;bioinformatics software engineer&amp;rdquo; for the JBrowse project. I became involved in bioinformatics in college, and did a senior thesis project analyzing ChIP-seq data. After graduating, I attended the GMOD Summer School in 2013 which introduced me to JBrowse, WebApollo, and the rest.
As a developer on the JBrowse project, I enjoy the high quality software engineering work that we do, and take pride in making complex data visualization easy and accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elliot Hershberg</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/elliot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/elliot/</guid>
      <description>I am a scientist and engineer with a broad range of experience in the life sciences and genomics. I have worked on problems ranging from basic science to technology development. I got my start in research studying the molecular genetics of cancer metastasis. After that, I worked on developing vaccines for cancer at the Cancer Vaccine Institute at the University of Washington. More recently, I worked as a Research Scientist/Engineer in the Department of Genome Sciences at the University of Washington.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garrett Stevens</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/garrett/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/garrett/</guid>
      <description>After graduating with my undergraduate degree in physics (with an emphasis in biophysics), I found myself drawn toward genomics. That led me to pursue a Masters degree in Bioinformatics through Brandeis University&amp;rsquo;s online program, where I developed my passion for bioinformatics software.
I joined the JBrowse team in 2018, just before work on JBrowse 2 started. I very much enjoy the remote format of the JBrowse development team, and am currently living in my home state of Utah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Evolution</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/project/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/project/evolution/</guid>
      <description>A natural question for a mathematical scientist, in any field with enough data, is: what are the underlying dynamics, and the equations describing them? For Newtonian systems, this gives us the laws of motion; for statistical mechanics, we get Brownian motion and diffusion.
In molecular evolution, the underlying dynamics involve sequences, populations, and trees. The equations describe mutation of sequences, migration of lineages, and genealogical coalescence of samples. These equations are necessarily statistical in nature; both because evolution is inherently random, and also because (as in statistical physics) we can approximate a lot of the complicated deterministic parts with random models too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanopore Informatics</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/project/nanopore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/project/nanopore/</guid>
      <description>Why long reads are important
 Structural variants in cancer Directed evolution Metagenomics Immunogenomics  What projects we work on
 Single-molecule basecalling Visualization of SVs Nanopore sequencing and directed evolution  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter Xie</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/peter/</guid>
      <description>I joined the JBrowse team in late 2019 in the midst of getting JBrowse 2 Web ready for release. I have been involved in bioinformatics and software development since college as it was a perfect blend of my major and minor. I started gravitating towards software development in my professional life which lead me to working with JBrowse. As a developer I enjoy working in a closely knit team where each member is passionate about the project and helping out the open source community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Biology</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/project/protein/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/project/protein/</guid>
      <description>Synthetic biology is fundamental to the technology of the 21st century. There are many challenges before we can realize rational design of biological systems. At the same time, biology allows for some additional engineering techniques, such as directed evolution, which have yet to be fully exploited.
We are interested in developing bioinformatics tools and infrastructure for synthetic biology including AI, ontologies, information theory, statistical machine learning, deep learning, and web technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teresa De Jesus Martinez</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/member/teresa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/member/teresa/</guid>
      <description>As an undergraduate, I quickly became fascinated in the application of computer science to solve biology based problems which led to me to take interest in bioinformatics and biomedical imaging.
After completing my degree at Berkeley, I moved to Washington D.C to work as a software engineer. During my time there, I began to experiment with web development tools and devOps to build full stack applications and micro services.
I joined the JBrowse team in 2020 right before the first release of JBrowse2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Genomics</title>
      <link>https://ihh.github.io/project/jbrowse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ihh.github.io/project/jbrowse/</guid>
      <description>Our work developing web-based visualizations of genomic data is based on observation of how the consumer web has transformed user interface design. Genome sciences are fundamental to the 21st century, so why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t genome scientsts enjoy web tools that are as sophisticated as those used for web-based word processors, spreadsheets, and maps?
This is not just a frivolous issue: the consensus doctrine of web app design that has emerged in the early 21st century includes many lessons about issues such as navigational continuity and dynamic data representation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
